我们在之前的讲座中谈过透视投影。这是转型
We've talked in earlier lectures about perspective projection. This is the transformation of
将三维世界中的点分成二维图像。并涉及损失
points in a three-dimensional world into a two-dimensional image. And involves the loss
它会导致诸如在三维中平行的线条等人工制品的尺寸
of a dimension it leads to artefacts such as lines which are parallel in the three-dimensional
世界似乎聚集在二维图像或三维投影中
world appearing to converge in the two-dimensional image or projection of that three-dimensional
世界。
world.
这里的另一个例子是一堆平行线，平行的三个树干似乎会聚
Another example here a bunch of parallel lines, parallel three trunks which appear to converge
在某一点上。我们早就谈到了针孔成像模型。我们有一个三维的
at a point. We talked early on about the pinhole imaging model. We have a three-dimensional
场景和它投射成二维图像。透视没有独特的反转
scene and it projects into a two-dimensional image. There is no unique inverse of the perspective
投影。任何数量的不同三维模型都将导致完全相同的二维模型
projection. Any number of different three-dimensional models will lead to exactly the same two-dimensional
投影。缺乏独特的逆是透视投影的重要结果。
projection. The lack of a unique inverse is really important consequence of the perspective projection.
对于机器人来说，了解三维世界非常重要。机器人需要
For robotics, knowledge of the three-dimensional world is really important. A robot needs to
知道它想要掌握的物体有多远。移动机器人需要知道是否
know how far away is the object that it wants to grasp. A mobile robot needs to know whether
它前面的空间可以自由驱动，或者那里是否有障碍物。
the space in front of it is free to be driven in or whether there is an obstacle there.
因此，我们在本次讲座中可以发现的重要话题是我们如何恢复第三个问题
So the important topic that we can uncover in this lecture is how do we recover the third
尺寸。当我们捕获图像时，在透视投影过程中丢失了这一点。
dimension. That’s been lost in the perspective projection process when we capture an image.